How…
怎麼會…
How are you all right?
妳怎麼會沒事？
Are you really okay?
妳真的沒事嗎？
What a relief…
真是謝天謝地
that at the very least you're okay.
我好高興妳沒事
I'm so relieved.
真是太好了
Wan-jin!
婉珍
Hey, what am I doing here?
我為什麼會在這裡？
How did you get so hammered?
妳怎麼醉成這樣？
-Are you sober? -Yes.
-你沒喝酒吧？ -沒有
Carry her.
你揹她吧
-Sang-man, grab her wheelchair. -Okay.
-相萬，拿好她的輪椅 -好
It must've been hectic because of us. I'm sorry.
因為我們的關係 情況一定亂糟糟，我很抱歉
I'll get going then.
再見了
Wait, take this too.
等等，別忘記這個
Hey.
喂
-Please take her home safely. -Aren't you coming?
請把她安全送到家
So it turns out. Bye.
是啊，再見
Oh, I'll walk you home, Mun-su. It's dangerous at night.
文秀，我陪妳走回家吧，晚上不安全
No, I'm fine. You should go home.
不用了，我沒事，你回家吧
I can't. Gang-du said we can't let a woman go alone at night.
不行啦，康斗說我們不該讓女孩子 晚上自己一個人走
Go upstairs. I'm a bit worried about him.
上樓吧，我有一點擔心他
Did you see it too?
妳也有看到嗎？
Sorry?
你說什麼？
Never mind.
算了
In that case, let Gang-du know when you get home.
既然這樣，當妳到家後 請跟康斗說一聲
What about Mun-su?
文秀呢？
She said she's fine.
她說可以自己回去
How can you let her go alone this late at night?
這麼晚了你怎麼能讓她自己走回家？
If you're both worried about each other, why didn't you go?
既然你們都這麼擔心對方
Gang-du!
康斗
Again? Do you hear voices again?
又發作了嗎？
Where is he?
他在哪？
Gang-du, can you see him?
康斗，你能看見他嗎？
Why is he doing this to you?
他為什麼要這樣做？
Can you just say sorry to him?
你不能就跟他道個歉嗎？
No, it's too late.
不行
He won't accept your apology?
他不接受你的道歉嗎？
What a bad person.
這個人真差勁
-Right? -Yes, he's bad.
-可不是嗎？ -對，他好差勁
He's really bad. Don't hang out with him.
他真的很差勁，別跟他玩了
-I shouldn't? -Never mind.
-是吧？ -算了
You should still apologize.
你還是該道歉
Apologize until he accepts your apology.
道歉到他接受為止
I'm sure your friend got angry
我相信你朋友之所以生氣
because you did something wrong.
是因為你做錯了什麼事情
-Over there. -Gang-du!
-在那邊 -康斗
Apologize to him now!
快跟他道歉！
-Hello. -You're here.
-你好 -你來了
-Is it ready?
-準備好了嗎？
Not yet.
還沒有
Hello.
大家好
You're here.
妳來啦
Mr. Seo! When did you get…
徐先生，你什麼時候…
You didn't go home last night?
你昨晚沒回家對吧？
Let's have a meeting.
我們先開會吧
We're revising the entire plan.
我們要重新修改整個設計
-Sorry? -What?
-你說什麼？ -什麼？
What's going on?
發生什麼事情了？
That's impossible, Mr. Seo.
徐先生，那是不可能的
We've only received 50% of the design cost.
我們只收到50%的設計費
If we don't meet the deadline,
若無法在交期內完成
the contractor will reevaluate our relationship.
承包商會質疑我們的能力
Our subcontractors have already started working.
我們的轉包商也開工了
There are countless reasons why we can't do that. I know.
我知道我們有很多理由不該這樣做
The materials we received for planning are different from the ones actually onsite.
我們在設計中所要的物料
It's not our fault, so we can let it go.
這不是我們的錯 我們是可以忽略這一點
If there's trouble,
但萬一發生問題
then could we let that go too?
我們也可以卸責嗎？
Are you going to start by examining the subsurface report again?
要回頭從檢查地面下報告開始嗎？
MONTHLY SCHEDULE
（月行事計畫表）
Revising the entire plan?
重新修改整個計畫？
No, just report on the progress.
沒關係，只要報告進度就好
Report on what?
報告什麼東西？
None of your business.
不關你的事情
She once hurt her head and lost a chunk of her memory.
她的頭部曾經受過傷 導致部分記憶喪失
I need to check. Who is he?
我要確定一下
Lee Gang-du.
李康斗
Our brand's image was reflected through the building. We're very pleased.
我們的品牌形象 完全透過建築表現出來
We hope Cheongyu will take the job for our centers next year.
我們希望清州 明年也能設計我們的中心
Sure. Please give me a second.
當然，請恕我失陪一下
This was the first building Mr. Seo designed.
這是徐先生設計的第一棟大樓
He was a rookie, but he wasn't confused or unconfident like he is now.
他當時還是菜鳥
I get that he's doing his best to do everything perfectly.
我知道他盡全力想把每件事做到完美
But Ju-won can't take responsibility alone.
但不該是周元扛下所有責任
Are we here to talk shit about him?
我們是在說他的壞話嗎？
Do I look that low?
我看起來有這麼卑鄙嗎？
I called you to help him.
我叫你來是要你幫他
-Before you report to Ju-won, contact me-- -I don't want to.
在你跟周元報告之前，先聯絡我…
There's an order to how we do our jobs.
做事情是要照順序的
If he turns the project around like this, it'll fail.
若他像這樣推翻整個案子 絕對會失敗
Is that bad?
有這麼糟嗎？
If you're going to fail anyway, isn't it better to save face?
如果怎樣都無法做成
Mr. Jung isn't an easy man to deal with.
要跟鄭先生周旋不容易
I don't approve either, but to do this--
我也不贊同，但這樣做…
Just because we hate the same guy
只是因為我們都討厭同一個人
doesn't put us on the same team.
那並不表示我們是一國的
But if we like the same person,
若我們都喜歡同一個人
can't we work together for now?
那為何不能就此合作呢？
We both like Mr. Seo, don't we?
我們都很欣賞徐先生，不是嗎？
-Aren't you here to see Mr. Seo? -I came to drop you off.
-妳不是也要找徐先生嗎？ -我是送你過來而已
It kills me to always visit him first.
每次都是我先去找他，太傷自尊心了
If he needs me, he'll come.
若他需要我，他會來找我
You're running errands? Here.
妳出去跑腿了？給我
No, I got it.
不用，我拿就好
You're stubborn for a tiny person. Give it to me.
妳人小竟然這麼固執，給我吧
Stop calling me tiny. I'm just petite.
不要說我小，我只是個子小
Here.
拿去
This is yours.
這是妳的
What are you doing?
你在幹嘛？
Aren't you here to see Mr. Seo?
你不是來找徐先生的嗎？
One second.
等一下
Don't wake him up.
別叫醒他
Let him sleep.
讓他睡
I can just ask you.
我問妳就好
You haven't even had lunch?
妳還沒吃午餐嗎？
Everyone is too busy revising the blueprint.
大家都忙著在修改藍圖
What's your question?
你要問什麼問題？
It's because I'm not too familiar with this.
是因為我不太清楚這種事情
Which is the most urgent?
哪一個比較趕？
This one.
這一個
Mr. Seo even went to the factory and put in the order,
徐先生去過工廠下訂單
but the deadline was tight.
但交期很趕
So we can start working if we have this?
若有了這個，我們就可以動工了嗎？
Yes.
對啊
Are you leaving?
你要走了嗎？
Eat slowly.
慢慢吃
-Sir. -Oh, hello.
-先生 -你們好
Have you been well?
你們好嗎？
Well, I'm looking for some materials.
我在找某種物料
Please take a look.
請看一下
-Can you find it? -This?
-你們這邊有嗎？ -這個嗎？
No, this one.
不是，是這個
If you find any, please let me know.
若你們有看到，請跟我說
-Sure. -Thank you.
-當然好 -謝謝
-Hello, Chief. -Hey, Gang-du.
-大哥，你好 -康斗
-Doing all right? -Yes.
-都還好嗎？ -很好
Everything going well?
一切都好嗎？
-I'm here to ask you a question. -Sure.
-我來這裡問你一個問題 -好啊
-That doesn't come in. -It doesn't?
-我們不會進這種東西 -不會嗎？
All right. Thank you.
好，謝謝
Why did you tag along only to waste your time?
妳幹嘛跟來浪費自己的時間？
You should go.
妳先走吧
No, we're leaving together.
不，要走就一起走
How pathetic.
真可悲
I have no connections, skills,
我沒人脈、沒技能
education, and my leg is like this.
也沒念多少書，加上我的腿又這樣
How can I have literally nothing?
我怎麼會一無所有？
There's nothing I can do on my own.
根本沒一件事情能靠我自己完成
That's not the case.
那不是真的
There are people who have all those,
有些人什麼都有
but turn away and refuse to help.
卻視而不見，不肯幫忙
You're such a decent person.
你是一個好人
BULLETIN
（佈告欄）
JINSU SHIPPING CONTAINERS AUCTION
（俊佑貨運貨櫃拍賣）
CONTAINERS ARE UP FOR AUCTION DUE TO JINSU'S BANKRUPTCY
（因為俊佑貨運破產）
What is it?
怎麼了？
SINHANG TRANSPORTATION
（新韓運輸中心）
Hello.
你好
When Jinsu Shipping went bankrupt, the containers got stuck.
當俊佑貨運破產，貨櫃都動不了
Their clients gave up because of litigation expenses.
因為訴訟費用的關係 他們的客戶都不想管了
And the auction failed, so we can't even get paid for the goods.
拍賣也開不成 所以這些貨也沒讓我們收到錢
Every time I see those things, it pisses me off.
我每次看到它們都一肚子火
That's why we couldn't pay you.
所以我們才沒辦法付你錢
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
This is it.
就是這個了
All right, now.
好了
Anyway, why do you need these?
不過你為什麼需要這些東西？
I heard the client is in Gyeongsan, someone who imports building materials.
我聽說這個貨主在慶山進口建築物料
Really?
是嗎？
-Are these the ones? -Yes.
-這些東西是我們要的嗎？ -是
How will you move all these?
你要怎麼把這些都運走？
Don't worry. My dad was a truck driver.
不要擔心，我爸當過卡車司機
But I am worried.
但我很擔心
Your dad was a truck driver, not you.
妳爸當過卡車司機，又不是妳
I'm licensed.
我可是有執照的
Really?
真的嗎？
Gosh.
天啊
This is huge.
車內好寬敞
No, you're tiny.
不是，是妳很嬌小
Let's just call a driver.
我們還是找個司機來吧
They'll feel awkward because of the chief and say no. Who can we call?
他們會看主管臉色然後拒絕 我們能找誰？
-Let's go. -Hey, wait. One second.
-走吧 -等等，再等一下
You'd better drive slowly. Just drive slowly no matter what.
妳最好慢慢開，不管怎樣都慢慢開
Okay?
好嗎？
It sounds so cool too.
聲音聽起來也很酷
It was tough, but I'm glad I got licensed.
過程雖不簡單 但我很開心我拿到了駕照
Let's go.
我們走吧
Why won't they go?
他們為什麼不動？
-Is it okay if I honk? -Why?
-我該按喇叭嗎？ -為什麼要按？
My gosh, come on. Why?
天啊，拜託，幹嘛按？
Did you see? Everyone got scared and moved.
你有看到嗎？大家都嚇到閃一邊去了
-Goodness. -This is so cool.
-我的老天 -開卡車太酷了
I saw it. Eyes on the road and drive.
我看到了，開車眼睛請看路
You must've gone insane.
妳一定是瘋了
Don't worry. Even if I get myself killed,
別擔心，就算我自己死了
I won't harm other people.
我也不會拖累別人
You called them without materials just to dig the ground?
又沒有物料 你還叫他們來開挖地面？
We're getting ready to start as soon as it arrives.
我們是在準備 等物料一到就可以開工
Yes, but when will it get here?
對，但什麼時候物料才會來？
So why did you change the supplier?
你為什麼要換掉供應商？
Just do as we did.
就照我們的方式做
I know it's easier,
我知道若是照舊
cheaper, and more effective to continue as we always have.
是比較簡單、便宜又更有效率
But it can also be dangerous.
但也可能很危險
Man, he's driving me crazy.
天啊，快把我逼瘋了
Mr. Seo, don't be so smart.
徐先生，不要太自以為是
The materials passed the inspection, and you call it dangerous?
物料都通過了檢驗
How can we start building, then?
那我們怎麼能施工呢？
Do you think the materials you want will suddenly fall from the sky?
你認為你要的物料
Hey, stop honking.
別按喇叭了
-Thank you. -Sure.
-謝謝 -不客氣
-Keep it up. -Thank you. Bye.
-繼續加油 -謝謝，再見
You like it that much?
妳這麼開心啊？
Take a picture for me.
幫我拍張照吧
You've got to be kidding me.
我不敢相信妳想這樣做
A photo with this truck?
跟卡車拍照？
Okay, I'll take it.
好，我要拍囉
One, two…
一、二…
No, go over to this side.
不行，往這邊一點
Yes, right there.
對，就是那裡
One, two…
一、二…
Hey, can't you smile?
妳不能笑一個嗎？
Smile like this.
像這樣笑
Okay, I'll take it.
好，我要拍了
One, two, three.
一、二、三
One more.
再一張
NOODLES AND GIMBAP
（麵食和海苔飯捲）
-Dad. -Yes?
-爸爸 -幹嘛？
Back when you were a truck driver, do you remember stopping by
你還是卡車司機的時候 你記得有沒有去過
Sintanjin Service Area?
新灘津休息站嗎？
Their pollack soup was delicious.
他們的鱈魚湯很好喝
That's the place for pollack soup.
要喝鱈魚湯就要去那裡
Don't you want to go?
你不想再去嗎？
You're always here. Doesn't it get suffocating?
你老是在這裡，不會覺得很悶嗎？
I drove a truck today, and I thought of you.
我今天開了卡車，就想到了你
You were so cool back then.
你以前好酷
Cool? Hardly.
很酷？才怪
I was always on the road, so I never got to see you two.
我老是在路上，我都沒時間照顧妳們
Because you had to work.
那是因為你必須要工作
It wasn't anything grand.
那不是什麼了不起的工作
I had no idea how my kids had grown up…
我錯過了我孩子的成長
or how she died.
也不知道她是怎麼離世的
There's no use in discussing this.
現在講這些都沒用了
It's not like I can turn back time.
我又沒辦法回到過去
Hello.
歡迎光臨
-Two spicy noodles. -Sure.
-兩碗辣麵 -好的
I took these for nothing. I wanted to show these to him.
拍了照也等於白照 我本來想給他看的
Who was it?
那是誰？
Who took that picture? You're smiling so beautifully.
拍照的人是誰？妳笑得好開心
GALAXY INN
（銀河客棧）
Why are our signs turned off? Did we close already?
妳的招牌為什麼不亮？ 我們已經關門了嗎？
When I fix one, another one breaks.
當我修好一個地方，另一處就壞了
Of all days,
還偏偏選今天
it only happens on the weekends.
這種事只在週末發生
The sauna is completely down.
三溫暖也沒辦法營業
We might have to close tomorrow too.
我們明天可能也開不了門
The sauna?
三溫暖？
Wow, you're much better than any old technician.
天啊，妳比那些老技工都還要棒
Leave it to me.
交給我吧
-Where else? -Over there. Down there.
還有哪裡？
Do you see the leak?
妳有看到漏水的地方嗎？
-This is pretty serious. -Can you fix it?
這挺嚴重的
Auntie, nothing is impossible.
阿姨，沒有事情是不可能的
Mun-su, there's nothing you can't do. You're a superwoman.
文秀，妳真是萬事通，簡直是女超人
-I don't want to be a superwoman. -What?
我可不想當女超人
It feels like I should be good at everything, when I'm not.
因為那得要樣樣精通，我可不是那樣
Why won't this work?
為什麼這一邊不動呢？
Then I'll call her later.
那我晚點再打
It's a bit awkward for me to go in.
直接走進去挺怪的
I just said Mun-su is too busy to come out…
我只是說文秀太忙了，沒辦法出來…
Oh my.
天啊
Why is her boss so young?
她的老闆怎麼這麼年輕？
-Come on in. -Oh, but still.
快請進
I wouldn't invite you in if people were naked.
若大家都沒穿衣服 我就不會邀請你進去了
-It's okay. Come on in. -Okay.
-沒關係，進來吧 -好
Just looking at him makes me feel reassured.
光看著他就覺得好放心
After only seeing short men around here,
我在這裡只見過矮小男人
it's nice to see a tall man for a change.
能看到高大的男人好耳目一新
You really don't have to.
你真的不需要這樣做
I'll feel more at ease once I do this for you.
等我幫妳修好後，我會覺得好一些
We wouldn't have gotten any work done if it weren't for you.
若不是因為妳 我們的工作也無法進行
It wasn't me. Gang-du--
其實不是我，康斗…
-Hey. -Yes?
-嘿 -幹嘛？
Look at those veins on his arms.
看看他手臂上的青筋
-Thank you so much. -Ask if he had dinner.
-非常感謝你 -問他吃過晚餐了沒
-What? -Dinner.
-問什麼？ -晚餐
Oh, have you had dinner?
你吃過晚餐了嗎？
Mom.
媽媽
I haven't eaten yet.
我還沒吃
You don't have to eat it all.
你不必通通吃完
Thank you. I haven't had a home-cooked meal in ages.
謝謝，我好久沒吃家裡煮的菜了
I'm just glad you finished everything.
我很開心你把菜都吃完了
Thank you. Thanks for your hard work.
謝謝，你太辛苦了
It was good. I mean it.
真的很好吃，我是說真的
Really?
是嗎？
Really, my foot. His mother is an excellent cook.
真的才怪，他媽媽廚藝一極棒
Not recently.
最近不同了
Her taste in food must've changed.
她對食物的喜好肯定是變了
Her food tastes too bland now.
她現在煮得都很清淡
-Should I pack some food? -I rarely eat at home.
-我幫你打包些食物吧？ -我幾乎不在家吃
But please do invite me again.
但請再邀請我過來吧
Goodness, you say the sweetest things, and you're so reliable.
天啊，你嘴巴好甜，真是值得信賴
Do you drink? Do you want some?
你會喝酒嗎？你想喝一點嗎？
Mom, Mr. Seo is a busy man.
媽，徐先生很忙的
Busy men can have a drink too, right?
忙碌的男人也能喝一杯，對吧？
-Everyone has a drink from time to time. -Yes.
-每個人偶而都會喝一杯 -對
-What's with you? -No, what's with you?
-妳怎麼了啊？ -哪有，妳又怎麼了？
You won't let me talk.
妳都不讓我說話
You're embarrassing me. Stop.
妳讓我很丟臉，別說了
Embarrassing you how?
哪裡讓妳丟臉了？
You keep saying weird things.
妳一直在說奇怪的話
CHILD MODEL HA YEON-SU DIES IN S MALL
（童星河妍秀死於S商場）
Goodbye.
再見
Mun-su.
文秀
-Do you have a sister? -Sorry?
-妳有妹妹嗎？ -你說什麼？
-Is it something difficult to talk about? -Yes.
-這個話題是否讓妳不自在？ -是的
Great work today, sir. Thank you.
老闆，今天工作辛苦了，謝謝你
Okay, then. See you tomorrow.
好，那明天見了
You're alone? Is he gone?
妳一個人嗎？他走了嗎？
Yes, I just saw him off.
對，我目送他離開了
Why do you look down?
妳幹嘛不高興？
I do? I must be tired.
有嗎？我大概是累了吧
-I got my hopes up for nothing. -What?
看來我高興得太早了
Life will get tiring enough when you two live together,
當兩個人住在一起生活是會覺得很累
so if you're already saying that,
若妳現在就已經這樣說
then there's no hope.
那就一點希望都沒了
Well, who cares about what others say?
也是啦，誰在乎別人怎樣說？
What's important is that you feel comfortable.
最重要的是妳高興就好
-Go inside. -Bye.
-進去吧 -再見
I should go. I'm leaving.
我該走了
Let me do it.
我來吧
-Mun-su. -Yes?
-文秀 -幹嘛？
I like him.
我喜歡他
My heart felt full even though I hadn't eaten a thing.
我什麼都沒吃，但我覺得好飽足
He's good at his job, and he's kind to his elders.
他的職業很不錯
He didn't seem married. Is he dating anyone?
他看起來不像結婚了，他有女友嗎？
Please. He's just my boss.
拜託一下，他是我的老闆
-Come on, Mom. -Why not?
-媽媽，拜託一下 -有何不可？
I want you to date a decent man without baggage like him.
我希望妳能跟這種 家世好的完美男人約會
Not that scruffy kid who looked like a puppy drenched in rain.
忘掉那個混小子吧 他看起來就像被雨淋濕的狗
Man. I'm getting sick of this.
天啊，這種東西看了就討厭
I want an actual meal.
我想吃頓正常的飯菜
Are we in a war?
我們在打仗嗎？
You haven't eaten?
你都還沒吃？
I brought you this because you threw a fit saying you're hungry.
你肚子餓在那亂發脾氣 所以我才買這些東西給你
I'm not eating this.
我不吃這種東西
You eat food like this and chain-smoke every day.
妳吃這種東西，又每天抽菸
How do you manage to stay healthy?
那妳怎麼保持身體健康？
Back in my day, these canned foods were hard to come by.
我們以前連這種罐頭食物都不夠吃
This is why childhood memories are important.
所以兒時記憶非常重要
Goodness, what a waste. I opened these for no reason.
我的天啊，真是浪費 打開了又沒人吃
What now? I opened them all.
現在怎麼辦？我全都打開了
I don't remember.
我不記得了
I don't remember any of good things from my childhood.
我不記得小時候有過任何好日子
I only remember the awful times.
我只記得苦日子
Gang-du.
康斗
It's been over 40 years since my husband died.
我丈夫已經死40多年了
I waited for the day to forget everything and be fine.
我一直在等自己哪天能放下一切 不再思念他
But do you know what I realized?
你知道我最後覺悟到什麼嗎？
That day won't come.
那一天不可能出現
If you can't make something happen, just leave it.
若沒辦法做到某些事情，就別管了
Don't try too hard.
不要強求
Sadness and pain are always around us.
我們總是會感受到悲傷和痛苦
Just accept it. What can we do?
接受它們吧，我們又能如何？
I feel wronged.
我覺得上天對我不公
Instead, you can meet a great person and live a more pleasant life.
可是你能遇見好的人 過著更愉快的生活
I know you'll be able to do that. Don't worry.
我知道你能做到的，不要擔心
What? Are you now a psychic too?
怎麼了？
I could be.
有何不可
Those who are my age might as well be psychics.
跟我同樣年紀的人都像算命師
Granny.
奶奶
What?
幹嘛？
Live long.
活久一點
MOKSAN CITY HOSPITAL
（木山市醫院）
You have lots of tests today.
今天有很多檢查要做
Are you feeling okay?
妳覺得還好嗎？
I'm used to it.
我都習慣了
Right, Gang-du's sister must be at this hospital.
對了，康斗的妹妹 應該在這家醫院上班
You're right.
沒錯
He definitely seems like a great guy.
他看起來像一個好人
Let's visit them again.
我們再去拜訪他們吧
They won't let us.
他們不會答應的
Do you know how awful you were that day?
妳知道妳那一天的情況有多糟嗎？
No idea. But it was fun. Isn't that good enough?
忘記了
It's not good enough.
那樣還不夠好
Don't you remember? Should I tell you?
妳不記得了嗎？要不要告訴妳？
No, that's not important.
不要，那又不重要
It was fun. That's all I need to remember.
我只要記得美好的回憶就好
-Wan-jin. -Yes?
-婉珍 -幹嘛？
Gang-du's father also passed away in that accident.
康斗的爸爸也因為那場意外離世了
Is that why the two of you ended up crossing paths?
所以你們才會認識嗎？
Did you tell him about your little sister?
妳有跟他說妳妹的事情嗎？
I did.
有
But it's weird.
但好奇怪
It doesn't feel bad when I talk to him about it.
跟他講這件事並不會覺得太難過
Sounds great. I guess you two were meant to be.
那很好
You two never say anything, but I'm sure you're both struggling.
你們都沒提過
Hey, I also…
我其實
feel sick whenever I see motorcycles.
每次看到摩托車都覺得很不舒服
Have you heard from that man?
妳有聽到那個人的消息嗎？
Not at all.
完全沒有
I'm sure I haven't heard from him because he's doing well.
我想沒聽到他的消息 就代表他沒事吧
I'm sure he's well.
我想他不會有事的
Time for your tests.
該做檢查了
You're both in this tiny bed?
妳們幹嘛都躺在這張小床上？
What if Ms. Kim falls?
若金小姐摔下來怎麼辦？
All right.
好了
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
I always make coffee for others,
我總為其他人泡咖啡
so it's my first time on the receiving end.
這是第一次有人泡咖啡給我喝
So? Isn't it good?
怎麼樣？很好喝吧？
You're a loafer who likes coffee and fishing.
你很愛玩，既愛煮咖啡又愛釣魚
How did you become a director?
你是怎麼當上董事的？
I can waste time like this because I'm a director.
我能這樣玩，就因為我是董事
There's nothing I can enjoy if I'm broke.
若我破產了就什麼都玩不了了
And yet you're very practical.
你也很實際
What's next?
接下來要幹嘛？
Let's get a camper and go see migratory birds.
去租臺露營車，然後去看候鳥吧
-Birds? -Yes.
-看鳥？ -對
Why won't you pick up?
你為什麼不接電話？
What's going on? How did you find me here?
怎麼了？妳怎麼知道我在這裡？
You always go to the same places. We need to talk.
你總是去老地方，我們得談談
I'm here for coffee. Please don't mind me.
我是來這裡喝咖啡的，請不用在意我
Darn it.
煩死了
CHEONGYU CONSTRUCTION
（清州建設公司）
What's this?
這是什麼？
The owner of the land by the road.
路邊那塊地的地主
Settle with them before they sue.
趁他們還沒告上法院前 去找他們洽談吧
I said I'll take care of it.
我說過我會處理的
And what did you do?
那你做了什麼？
Hey, get rid of that attitude.
請不要給我那種態度
Watch yourself. My wife wants to teach you a lesson
妳的嫂子都想教訓妳了
for being rude to her brother.
妳對她弟很無禮
You be careful. She knows of this place too.
你才最好小心點，她也知道這個地方
Be careful with what? She doesn't care about me.
小心什麼？她根本不在乎我
She won't care. It's fine.
她根本不在意，沒關係的
Even if she doesn't care,
就算她不在意
people can't stand it when others take what's theirs.
沒有人能忍受自己的東西 被其他人搶走
She looks too much like that woman.
她看起來很像那個女人
Don't play for too long. This smells dangerous.
不要玩太久，會玩出問題
LAND REGISTER
（地籍本）
NAMSAN-DONG, GEUMJEONG-GU
（南山洞、金井區）
Darn it, what is this?
該死，這是搞什麼？
Hello.
妳好
I can't believe we ran into each other!
我不敢相信我們又遇到了
I've been regretting not getting your number
我一直很後悔沒有跟妳要電話
because I had no other means to reach out and see you again.
因為我沒有其他方式聯絡和再見到妳
I left my number on your phone.
我把我的號碼輸入妳的手機了
Anyway, it must be fate we met like this
總之，一定是命運讓我們像這樣
without making plans.
再次巧遇
-This is great. -Sorry?
-太好了 -怎麼了嗎？
Come in for a second.
先過來吧
No, it's all right.
不，沒關係的
-I'll go after you go in. -I just feel bad.
妳先進去，我再進去
You're already here, so come in for some tea.
妳人已經在這了，進來喝杯茶吧
-Goodness. -I'm fine.
-我的天啊 -我沒關係的
Come on in.
進來吧
Goodness.
我的天啊
Where have you been? You told me to come.
妳去哪了？妳不是要我過來
-Why are you here? -What about you?
妳來這裡幹嘛？
Do you two know each other?
你們認識嗎？
Wait, how do you know each other?
等等，妳們怎麼會認識？
On the street, she--
在街上，她…
I asked her for directions on the street.
我問她路怎麼走
She could've just told me, but she walked me here,
她只要跟我說就好，但她陪我走過去
so I wanted to give her some tea. Why?
所以我想請她喝茶，不行嗎？
Goodness, I did that for nothing.
我的天啊，我幹嘛這樣浪費時間
Those who are meant to be will always end up meeting.
有緣份的人自然會相見
You both can leave.
你們可以走了
What? You told me to come.
什麼？妳叫我過來的
It gets dangerous after dark.
入夜後這裡很危險
You two can hold hands and leave together.
你們可以手牽手一起離開
What are you saying?
妳在講什麼？
I said you two can leave together. Don't make me repeat myself.
我說你們可以一起走了 幹嘛讓我一直重複說
I'm going to lie down. Leave together.
我要去休息了，一起走吧
Wait, what?
等等，搞什麼？
I didn't know you had a grandma.
我不知道你有個奶奶
She's not my grandma.
她不是我奶奶
She's more like a friend.
她比較像是朋友
I guess kids these days don't play in playgrounds. It's empty.
看來現在的小孩子 都不來公園玩了，都沒有人
Yeah.
真的耶
What a shame. Let's play instead of them.
真可惜
Your parents must've had a tough time.
你的父母當時一定很辛苦
What?
妳說什麼？
The back of your head is round like a baseball.
你的後腦勺很圓，就像棒球
They say it means you were never still.
那是因為你很好動，都不好好躺著
Or you must've cried all day long, so your mom probably had to hold you.
或你老是一天到晚哭 所以你媽得一直抱你
No idea.
不知道
I don't remember.
我不記得了
What about you?
那妳呢？
I was really quiet.
我以前很乖
If they put me down in the morning, I stayed there until night.
若我早上就躺著，就會一直躺到晚上
Really?
真的嗎？
Of course. I'm not like you.
當然，我又不像你
Then the back of your head must be totally flat.
那妳的後腦勺一定很扁
Hey, it really is flat.
真的很扁
Yes, good for you. Your head is round.
對啊，你就很好，頭那麼圓
You really were a nice kid.
妳以前真的是個乖孩子
OK-DONG INTERSECTION
（公車站：玉東十字路口）
Bye.
再見
Can you take the next bus?
妳可以搭下一班公車嗎？
I wasn't a nice kid.
我以前一點都不乖
What?
妳說什麼？
I have a huge hole in the back of my head.
我的頭後面有一個凹洞
You didn't know, right?
你不知道，對吧？
I heard I was hurt during the accident, but I don't remember.
因為意外發生時我受傷了
All I remember is…
我只記得
how I left my sister behind.
我拋下了我妹妹
That there was another person who couldn't return because of me.
還有一個人，因為我而沒辦法回家
But I'm here living my life as if nothing happened.
但我卻好好地活著 好像什麼都沒發生一樣
Aren't I horrible?
我是不是很差勁？
No.
不會
The hour of dreams and music.
現在是夢想和音樂的時間
It is now midnight.
現在是午夜
I love this moment when nothing happens…
我最喜歡這個時候的一片寂靜
as today becomes tomorrow.
明天變成了今天
So-mi.
素美
Can I use your lip gloss?
妳的唇蜜能借我嗎？
Thanks.
謝謝
You're going to the site today. Why do you need this?
妳今天要去工地，幹嘛擦唇蜜？
Wait, Mun-su. Your eye bags. No, let's begin with your cheeks.
文秀，等等，妳的黑眼圈
So we're revising the entire plan.
我們要重修整個設計
I wondered why you called first, and it was for this?
我還在想你怎麼先打來了？ 就因為這個嗎？
You have an eye for blueprints.
妳很會看藍圖
Do I still seem stubborn?
我依然很固執嗎？
Yu-taek is on site. Let's go.
潤澤在工地，我們走吧
This is enough to make me understand, but not Mr. Jung.
我光看就知道情況了 但對鄭先生來說可不同
Show him the problem on site and convince him.
在工地上跟他說問題點 然後試著說服他吧
My brother isn't so pathetic that he deserves to be looked down on.
我哥哥沒這麼可悲，不應該被人看輕
He wants this business to thrive more than anybody.
他比任何人都希望這個案子能夠成功
What is it?
有什麼事情嗎？
I'm sorry.
抱歉打擾了
-Did you put on makeup? -Oh, yes.
妳是不是化了妝？
Do I look weird?
是不是看起來很怪？
No, you look pretty.
不會，看起來很漂亮
I have to be on site.
我要去工地了
Don't fall in love with Ms. Ha.
別愛上河小姐了
You buy her meals and listen to her concerns.
你請她吃飯，聽她傾訴
But eventually you'll lose her to another man.
可是她心裡愛的是其他人
I don't want someone I love to play such a pathetic role.
我可不希望我喜歡的人在扮長腿叔叔
-What? -Ha Mun-su and Lee Gang-du.
-妳說什麼？ -河文秀和李康斗
Don't you know they like each other?
你不知道他們的事情嗎？
The street by the parking lot still belongs to someone.
停車場旁的街道依然是屬於別人的
Did you get their consent?
你有徵求過他們的同意嗎？
Once the investment is approved, we'll figure it out.
等到資金確定後，我們就會處理
Cheongyu bought this land back in the '90s,
清州在1990年代就買下這塊地
on the condition you'll clean up the buried waste.
附帶條件是你們要清理 所有掩埋在地下的垃圾
Was it taken care of?
那件事情處理好了嗎？
Is this a hearing?
這是聽證會嗎？
My staff are experts.
我的員工都是專家
Don't run your mouth after reading a few documents.
請不要因為看過幾張文件就妄下斷言
Then did the building collapse willy-nilly although there were experts?
你是說雖然有專家 大樓依然全坍塌下來了嗎？
Hey,
高層已經有決定了
I just called you here to sign the papers. That's all.
我只是叫你來這裡簽名而已
Got it?
懂了嗎？
Yes, Deputy Head.
對，副理事
It has been a while.
是有一陣子沒聯絡了
There's a bit of a problem here.
這裡出了一點問題
You look different.
妳看起來有點不一樣
What?
哪裡不同？
Have you become cuter?
是不是變得更可愛了？
Whatever.
隨便吧
Do you have the drainage plan?
你有排水設施圖嗎？
It's in the office.
在辦公室裡
It's not that way.
不是那個方向
Sir, but this is--
長官，但這是…
I'm sure about this project.
我對這個案子有信心
Our job is to let them borrow money and take the interest.
我們的工作 是讓他們借錢，然後收利息
Stop this nonsense.
別找麻煩了
I didn't…
我沒有…
We met back then.
我們之前有見過
You went around taking signatures for the memorial, and we meet again.
妳之前為了立紀念碑到處跑
Sorry?
你說什麼？
So like does attract like.
果然物以類聚
What is he saying? Who is this?
他在說什麼？他是誰？
Do you know about his dad?
妳知道他爸爸的事情嗎？
You look a lot like him.
你看起來跟他很像
Is it because your dad was human garbage?
是不是因為你爸爸也是敗類
His son is here working as their dog.
所以他的兒子 也在這裡當他們的走狗？
Hey.
嘿
Gang-du's dad was also a victim who passed away in the accident.
康斗的爸爸也是 在那場意外身亡的受害者
A victim?
受害者？
Who are you?
你是誰？
Your father is the murderer. A victim?
你爸爸明明就是殺人凶手，受害者？
-A victim? -You jerk!
-受害者？ -你這個混球
Man, you're strong.
天啊，你力氣真大
You must've lived a great life with the rebar your dad stole.
你大概因為你爸爸偷走的鋼筋 過上了不錯的生活
Did you?
王八蛋，是不是這樣？
Enough.
夠了
-Stop it! -I'll kill you!
-住手… -我會殺了你
Stop!
住手！
This building will collapse.
這棟大樓會倒塌的
Don't go.
別走
-Let me explain-- -No.
-請讓我解釋… -不要
Not now. Let's talk later.
現在不行，晚點再講
When?
什麼時候？
How are you so calm?
你怎麼這麼冷靜？
Did you know about Gang-du's father?
你之前就知道康斗爸爸的事情嗎？
How interesting.
真有意思
So you understood him?
所以你懂他的心情？
Then you should've jumped in
那你應該要出面解釋
so that he didn't suffer alone.
不是讓他一個人受苦
Coward.
膽小鬼
We always get into fights,
我們老是吵架
but Cheongyu is still big,
但清州依然最有權有勢
so you don't care?
所以妳不在乎嗎？
Watch what you say.
說話前請先想一想
You just didn't get punished, but your mistakes are still there.
沒有被懲罰，不代表你們就沒有錯
Let's go wash up.
一起去清理一下吧
Fire me if you want to.
想開除我就開除我吧
I don't care.
我不在乎
Why? Because of your father?
為什麼？
I already knew that.
我早就知道那件事情了
Did I look like a sloppy guy who would recruit you
我看起來像這麼隨便的人 什麼事情都不知道
without knowing that?
就僱用你來上班嗎？
Don't mind what he said.
別管他說的話
If the building had collapsed just because your dad stole some rebar…
若因為你爸爸偷走了幾條鋼筋 大樓就會倒塌
it would've collapsed anyway.
那不管怎樣終究都會倒
Even so, what my dad did wasn't right.
就算是這樣
I'm leaving. Saunas suffocate me.
我要走了
Lee Cheol-u? Who's that?
李哲佑？他是誰？
Lee Gang-du?
李康斗？
You idiot, why didn't you know as the chief?
你這個笨蛋 你做主管怎麼會不知情呢？
Forget that. Fire him immediately.
算了
The reason?
理由？
Because I don't like him!
因為我不喜歡他！
Fire him.
開除他
Fire him tomorrow.
明天就開除他
-Fire who? -None of your business.
-開除誰啊？ -不關妳的事情
Darn it, this place is full of psychos.
該死，這個地方到處是瘋子
Did you have a tough day?
你今天很累嗎？
This crazy idiot completely messed with my head,
這個瘋子把我的思緒都攪亂了
and I'm surrounded by enemies.
我身邊的人都是敵人
Life gets lonelier as you climb up the ladder, right?
本來就是職位爬得越高 就越來越孤單，不是嗎？
Right.
對
That's why you're lonely too.
所以妳也很孤單吧
You really know these things.
妳真的很瞭解這種事情
This is why I like you.
所以我才喜歡妳
Not because I'm like your first love?
不是因為我像你的初戀嗎？
You are, really.
妳的確很像
Mun-su, that's not the right blueprint.
文秀，不是那張藍圖
What's with me?
我到底是怎麼了？
Hello, Mr. Seo.
徐先生，你好
Mun-su.
文秀
Oh, yes?
怎麼了？
Do you want some coffee?
你想喝咖啡嗎？
Did you get some sleep?
妳有睡好嗎？
I did.
我有
Did you talk with Mr. Lee?
妳跟李先生談過了嗎？
I'm sure he…
我相信他…
Ha Mun-su and Lee Gang-du.
河文秀和李康斗
Don't you know they like each other?
你不知道他們的事情嗎？
Mr. Seo.
徐先生
Never mind. Get back to work.
算了，繼續工作吧
If you're free tonight…
若妳今晚有空
let's have dinner.
一起吃晚餐吧
Gang-du, do you feel sick?
康斗，你生病了嗎？
Like really sick?
病得很重嗎？
Yes, I'm sick.
對，我生病了
I might give it to you, so go.
我可能會傳染給你，快走吧
Should I call Mun-su and tell her that you're sick?
要不要我打給文秀 跟她說你生病了？
Don't call her. I mean it.
我說真的，不可以打給她
Gang-du, did you do something to make Mun-su mad?
康斗，你是不是做了什麼 讓文秀生氣的事情？
Did you two fight?
你們吵架了嗎？
Then you should hurry up and say sorry.
那你應該要趕快去道歉
That way, she'll feel better.
這樣她才會消氣
So what? Will that always work? Will it make her feel better?
道歉又能怎樣？
So apologize until she accepts your apology.
那就去道歉到她接受為止
How many times do I have to tell you?
我到底要跟你說幾次？
Are you sure you aren't a little slow?
你確定自己的腦袋沒問題嗎？
Goodness. How will you survive in this tough world?
哎呀
I'm worried sick about you.
我擔心死你了
GANG-DU
（康斗）
Are you going to get that?
妳不接電話嗎？
If you won't, just turn it off.
若不接，就按拒接吧
I'm going to go eat noodles tonight.
我今晚要去吃麵
I'm not asking you to come. But I'll just wait.
我不是要妳來找我，但我會等妳
Did you have something to say to me?
你有事情要跟我說嗎？
No, I just wanted to eat with you.
沒有，只是想跟妳吃個飯
Your mother seemed very nice.
妳媽媽看起來很漂亮
I bet she was a beauty in her youth.
她以前一定是大美女吧
Do you take after her?
妳是遺傳到她嗎？
When I was young, I was jealous of kids whose parents ran a sauna.
我小時候很羨慕家裡經營澡堂的小孩
Did you and your friends…
妳跟妳的朋友…
Mun-su.
文秀
Mun-su?
文秀？
Sorry?
你說什麼？
Well, Mr. Seo.
徐先生
I'm sorry, but I have to go.
我很抱歉，但我得先走了
I have to be somewhere,
我得去一個地方
and I think I should go.
我認為我該過去
At this hour? Where?
這個時候嗎？去哪？
To see my dad.
去看我爸爸
No, I'll go alone.
不了，我自己去就好
It's tough to find a taxi at this hour.
這麼晚了很難叫到計程車
If you're getting a cab, let me drop you off.
若妳要坐計程車，就乾脆讓我送妳吧
Your eldest took after you.
你的大女兒長得像你
She looks much better.
她長得好看多了
She had her share of trouble.
她之前過得很痛苦
I hope she'll live a comfortable and happy life.
我希望她以後能過著幸福快樂的生活
If you're done, you should go. Don't mind her.
若你吃完了就走吧，別想著她了
Do you take after your dad or your mom?
妳是像妳爸爸，還是像妳媽媽？
My dad. I look exactly like him.
我爸爸
Over there. You can drop me off there.
就在那裡
Thank you. Drive safely.
謝謝你，開車小心
Mun-su.
文秀
-Do you remember anything I said tonight? -Sorry?
妳記得我今天說過的話嗎？
I knew you wouldn't.
我就知道妳不記得
So I felt offended.
這讓我有一點不高興
I hate it when you think of someone else in front of me.
我不喜歡妳在我面前想著其他人
It feels awful.
這種感覺很糟
SPECIAL THANKS TO KIM JIN-WOO AND JO SU-AE
（特別感謝金秦禹和趙秀愛）
Everyone does the same thing when they're rejected.
當人被拒絕都會做一樣的事情
I wasn't rejected.
我沒有被拒絕
But don't just run away. I'll be rooting for you, Mr. Lee.
那就別這樣逃跑 李先生，我會為你加油的
I am going to run away. That's the better choice for Mun-su.
但我會走，文秀有更好的選擇
Don't lurk around here. Go be with Mr. Seo.
別來這裡等，去找徐先生吧
-It's better-- -Why do you get a say?
-這樣比較好… -你憑什麼替我決定？
Then our relationship meant nothing?
我們的感情一點意義都沒有嗎？
I was the only one who had feelings for you?
只是我在單戀你嗎？
You led me on. You're a huge jerk.
你這個大混球 是你讓我進入你的生命
I'm so furious. He didn't do anything wrong, so why am I angry?
我好生氣，他什麼都沒做 為什麼我這麼生氣？
Then just be mad!
那就生氣吧
Why do you hold back?
幹嘛要忍住？
And if I get angry? What if he's disappointed in me?
若他對我覺得失望怎麼辦？
I might lose him forever.
我也許會永遠失去他
Don't you know Gang-du?
妳還不瞭解康斗嗎？
He wasn't disappointed in you.
他怎麼可能對妳失望
He never lets anyone in, worried that he'll ruin them too.
他從不讓任何人靠近 因為擔心自己會毀了他們
If he keeps you at a distance,
若他跟妳疏離
it means he cherishes you that much.
那是因為他非常珍惜妳